<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Bigger Than Yourself</title>
    <link>http://biggerthan.micahbarett.info</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 01:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
    
    <item>
      <title>Océ</title>
      <link>http://biggerthan.micahbarett.info/resources/oce</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2014 21:23:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Micah Barrett</author>
      <guid>http://biggerthan.micahbarett.info/resources/oce</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/%7EOce%20TDS%20400-450%20191103-%20%20018.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;~Oce TDS 400-450 191103-  018&quot;&gt; 
As I&amp;rsquo;m sure many of you are familiar by now, large format printing can be extremely expensive. Most print shops however stock a machine that is significantly less expensive than the high resolution photo printers we&amp;rsquo;re used to using. The Océ printer is a large format black and white printer generally used for architectural drawings. It&amp;rsquo;s crude, but only 75 cents per square foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alphagraphics and FedEx Office both have these. The roll is 36&amp;quot; wide, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how long it can go &amp;mdash; might be worth trying.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crit Forms</title>
      <link>http://biggerthan.micahbarett.info/resources/crit-forms</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2014 15:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Micah Barrett</author>
      <guid>http://biggerthan.micahbarett.info/resources/crit-forms</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Crit forms should be filled out and turned in to Fred Flori in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://info.risd.edu/facilities-operations/&quot;&gt;facilities office&lt;/a&gt; on the 2nd floor of What Cheer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They can be downloaded here:
&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/Installation%20Site%20Permit-1.pdf&quot;&gt;Installation Site Permit-1&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vinyl Cutting</title>
      <link>http://biggerthan.micahbarett.info/resources/vinyl-cutting</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 10:21:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Micah Barrett</author>
      <guid>http://biggerthan.micahbarett.info/resources/vinyl-cutting</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/graphtec-ce6000-120-vinyl-cutter.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;graphtec-ce6000-120-vinyl-cutter&quot;&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vinyl cutters in the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concept Link&lt;/strong&gt;: Now in the 2nd floor of the Design Center, Concept Link offers large format printing as well as vinyl cutting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AS220 Labs&lt;/strong&gt;: In addition to laser cutting, AS220 Labs also has a vinyl cutter which is available for use after attending a &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.as220.org/collections/workshops-as220-labs/products/introduction-to-the-vinyl-cutter&quot;&gt;one day course&lt;/a&gt;. You may also hire the Labs staff to produce cut vinyl for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Laser Cutting</title>
      <link>http://biggerthan.micahbarett.info/resources/laser-cutting</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 10:19:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>Micah Barrett</author>
      <guid>http://biggerthan.micahbarett.info/resources/laser-cutting</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a few laser cutting options in the area. Here&amp;rsquo;s a rundown of each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BEB&lt;/strong&gt;: The RISD Architecture department has a laser cutter in the bottom floor of the BEB. Architecture students take priority so it might be difficult to get time on the machine without an ambassador in the department. Payment is based on time on the machine so more intricate designs will take much longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bud at Precision Laser&lt;/strong&gt;: Up in Pawtucket, Precision Laser is a one man shop run by Bud. He sounds cranky over the phone but is extremely helpful. It&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to give him several days lead time on your piece, and usually he&amp;rsquo;ll surprise you with a call letting you know it&amp;rsquo;s done early. Let him know that you&amp;rsquo;re a RISD student up front and he&amp;rsquo;ll ask you to pay what you can. Please don&amp;rsquo;t take advantage of this generosity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.precisionlaserri.com/&quot;&gt;Precision Laser&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AS220 Labs&lt;/strong&gt;: The Labs at AS220 also has a laser cutting facility along with vinyl cutting, 3D printing, and a CNC router. The facilities are available for use after &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.as220.org/collections/workshops-as220-labs&quot;&gt;taking a two session course on each machine&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, you can &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.as220.org/labs/about/&quot;&gt;hire the monitors/shop managers to cut material for you&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Materials for cutting can be purchased at the RISD 3D store or online through &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.inventables.com/&quot;&gt;Inventables&lt;/a&gt;. The RISD Materials Resource center on the 2nd floor of the Fleet Library has a comprehensive swatch book of the materials stocked by Inventables if you wish to see physical samples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please ask any store you purchase acrylic from if it&amp;rsquo;s safe to be used on a laser cutter and be sure to verify with the cutter that they&amp;rsquo;re comfortable cutting your material. Wood has a tendency to burn on the edges and some pieces of plexi won&amp;rsquo;t be able to be cut as they will emit toxic fumes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
